

Fiacre Nsanzabandi

Date of birth: 11/07/1988 | Nationality: Burundian | Gender: Male |

(+49) 15752082517 | fayabobo@gmail.com | https://fiacre-nsanzabandi.com |

8, Arensstraße, 33142, Büren, Germany

About me: I am a software engineer experienced in JavaEE programming. After 7 years of professional life in application development, I find it easy to integrate new projects and quickly acquire new knowledge on new subjects. I consider myself a dynamic, versatile and autodidact person and that allows me to be a very good team player. I like sharing the developer experience and it motivates me to move towards the professions of "tech leader", "team leader" or "scrum master".

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/10/2021 - CURRENT - Paderborn, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - INCONY AG

I work on the development of our products. For more information, please visit us at https://www.incony.de

01/05/2019 - 30/09/2021 - Leudelange, Luxembourg

DEVELOPER FOR DIFFERENT CUSTOMERS AND INTERNAL PROJECTS – SOPRA STERIA

Clients

- SIB (Steria interconection box)
- Sopra Steria academy
- UCM (Union des classes moyennes)
- Sopra Steria digilab
- BCP Luxembourg

Tasks

- Conception & development of Java EE applications
- Java trainer for the Sopra Steria academy
- Participation in different POCs (Proof of concepts) aimed at improving the existing

Technical environment:

- WEB programming: Java EE, Spring batch, Spring boot, Angular, HTML5, CSS3
- **Mobile programming:** Android
- IT Ops & cloud: Docker, kubernetes, Google cloud platform, Ansible
- Collaboration & integration: Git, Jira, Jenkins 2, Maven, SVN
- Database: Oracle, Mysql

Methodology: Agile, scrum

01/01/2018 - 30/04/2019 - La Madeleine, France

DEVELOPER FOR THE CUSTOMER "ONEY BANK" – SOPRA STERIA

Tasks

- Conception & development of JavaEE applications
- Technical leader in clean coding

Technical environment

- WEB programming: Java EE, Spring boot, Spring batch, HTML5, CSS3, Angular JS
- Collaboration and integration: Git, Jira, Jenkins 2, Maven
- Database: Oracle, Mysql

Methodology: Agile

Customer's domain: Banking

DEVELOPER FOR THE CUSTOMER « GIE AGORA » (IT CENTER OF THE MUTUAL HEALTH INSURANCE FOR FARMERS IN FRANCE) – SOPRA STERIA

Tasks

- Conception & development of JavaEE applications
- Provide corrective maintenance
- Evolutions' costing
- WEB technical leader for new developers
- Analyst and team leader

Technical environment

- WEB Programming: Java EE, Struts, Spring batch, HTML5, CSS3, C etc.
- Database management tools: COBOL, DB2, CICS
- Collaboration and integration: Jira, CVS
- Applications' performances: |Meter & |Profiler.

Methodology: Agile

Customer's domain: Insurance

03/03/2014 - 31/01/2016 - La Madeleine, France

DEVELOPER FOR THE CLIENT « AG2R LA MONDIALE » - SOPRA STERIA

Tasks

- Conception & development of JavaEE applications
- Provide corrective maintenance
- · Evolutions' costing
- WEB technical leader for new developers

Technical environment

- WEBprogramming: Java EE, GWT, JSF, Spring, HTML5, CSS3
- Database management tools: COBOL, DB2, CICS
- Collaboration & integration: Jira, ARS, ITSM, HPQC, clearcase, CVS

Functional environment: Insurance

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/09/2011 - 01/08/2014 - Rouen, France

MASTER'S DEGREE IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING - Université de Rouen

Professional studies on:

- software development methodologies
- various programming languages (WEB programming, Java, Java EE, C++, C#, etc.)

01/09/2008 - 01/07/2011 - Oran, Algeria

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN MATHEMATICS & COMPUTER SCIENCE - Université d'Oran

Programming:

- ∘ Java, C++, Qt
- Functional programming: prolog, CAML.

Mathematics: analyzes and algebra

Student scholarship of the Burundian government and UNESCO.

01/09/2007 - 01/06/2008

GAP YEAR

Student at the University of Tanganyika Lake; Traveling across East Africa.

SECONDARY STUDIES ACHIEVEMENT IN MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS - Lycée du Lac

Tanganyika

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): FRENCH | KIRUNDI | SWAHILI

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C1
GERMAN	B1	B1	B2	B2	B1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: AM
Driving Licence: B1
Driving Licence: B

SKILLS

Job-related skills

- **Programming languages**: Java, Kotlin, typescript, C++, C, C#, SQL, etc.
- **WEB programming**: JavaEE (JSP/Servlet, etc.), Spring (Spring boot, Spring MVC, etc.), Angular, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, etc.
- IT Ops & cloud: Docker, kubernetes, Ansible, Google cloud platform
- JavaEE tools & frameworks: Playframework, GWT, Zkoss, JUnit, AspectJ, SoapUI, postman etc.
- Profiling and performances: JMeter & JProfiler
- Mobile development: Android
- · Collaboration & integration: Git, CVS, Maven, Nexus, Sonar, Jenkins, Jira
- Project management: Agile methods (Scrum, XP)
- Development tools (IDE): Eclipse, Intellij
- Database tools: MySQL, Postgresql, Oracle, non-relational databases notions (eXist)
- Servers: Tomcat, TomEE, glassfish, JBoss, Weblogic
- OS: Linux & Windows

I am a full stack developer: 60% of my time doing javaEE and 40% working on other technologies.